Yeah. We got this.
一定能贏
...here at the MGM Grand tonight, Roy.
今晚可是光榮的拳王之夜 羅伊
And, you know, when Adonis Creed lost to "Pretty" Ricky Conlan,
你知道嗎 阿多尼斯·奎迪之前惜敗於「俊小子」裏基·康蘭
he was really a curiosity more than anything else.
但他的橫空出世 引起了大家的好奇
But that was an epic fight,
那真是一場激烈的比賽
and since then, he's reeled off six straight wins,
從那以後 他一口氣取得了六連勝的戰績
and tonight attempts against Danny "The Stuntman" Wheeler
而今晚他又將對戰「特技演員」丹尼·惠勒
to become the heavyweight champion of the world.
共同競爭世界重量級拳王寶座
It bears mentioning that Creed actually wagered his Mustang
值得一提的是 奎迪在上次與惠勒的熱身賽中
before their sparring session, Roy.
把自己的福特野馬都賭輸了 羅伊
And rumor has it that same Mustang is on the line again tonight.
據說這輛福特野馬 今晚又被惠勒當成了賭注
Okay, everybody out. Let's go.
好了 都出去吧 我們走
- Feel good? - Mmm-hmm.
- 還好嗎 - 好
Yeah. Remember to keep your right hand up, okay?
記住要一直出右拳 好嗎
His left is just as strong as his right.
他的左拳和右拳一樣厲害
- Yep. - Yeah.
好
- Mmm-hmm. - Mmm-hmm. Okay, good.
那就好
It's just another fight, okay?
保持平常心就行 好嗎
You got this.
你一定能贏的
You know, there's only three steps into that ring.
從台下到台上只有三個台階
Just three.
三個而已
And tonight, it's gonna look as high as a mountain.
可今晚它們會像山一樣高不可攀
And when you climb through them ropes,
當你鑽過圍繩之後
it's gonna be the loneliest place in the world
會立刻陷入孤立無援的境地
because you're gonna be in there with another fighter
因為站在你對面的拳手
who wants to take you out.
只想把你擊倒
So now, you gotta ask yourself,
現在你必須問問自己
are you here to prove something to other people
你來這兒到底是為了不辜負別人
or prove something to yourself?
還是為了無愧於自己
To myself.
我想無愧於自己
Right.
很好
Now, let me ask you something.
現在換我來問你問題
What?
你問
What's with the hair?
你頭髮怎麼了
I combed it. It's a special night.
我仔細梳了梳 今天可是大日子
Shouldn't you be thinking about something else, wise guy?
你是不是該操心點別的事 小滑頭
Now, you can go prove it.
好了 去證明自己
Now go get your Mustang back.
把你那輛野馬給贏回來
These guys have really been mixing it up here in the fourth.
兩位拳手在第四回合真是打得難解難分
So far, Creed's youth outweighing Wheeler's experience.
目前 年輕氣盛的奎迪壓制了經驗老到的惠勒
Let's go! Let's go, baby. Let's o!
逼他後退 加油 兄弟
Maybe the most amazing part of Adonis Creed's journey, Roy...
阿多尼斯·奎迪的這場比賽最振奮人心的地方
Don't drop that guard! Sit.
別放鬆 穩點
...is that tonight, he fights...
就在於他今晚的搏殺
Keep your hands up!
繼續出拳
...for the same belt held by both his trainer, Rocky Balboa,
是為了接過他的教練洛奇·巴爾博亞
and his father, the great Apollo Creed.
和他的父親 偉大的阿波羅·奎迪 都嬴過的那條金腰帶
Wheeler seems to be waking up. We've seen this before, Roy.
惠勒好像要發力反擊了 這一幕似曾相識 羅伊
When Wheeler smells blood, he really turns it on.
一旦發現機會 惠勒就會變得無人能擋
Come on back.
再來 繼續再打
Come on, D!
加油 多尼
Three years ago, that's a knockout.
放在三年前 奎迪就輸定了
Wheeler's power just isn't the same, and no doubt Creed can sense it.
可如今惠勒的力量已經不如以往 奎迪肯定也察覺到了這點
You got him. Stay on him!
他不行了 咬緊他
Creed's on a mission, really pressing the issue now.
奎迪是志在必得啊 現在簡直卯足了全力
And a big left hook lands flush!
他揮出了一記雷霆萬鉤的左勾拳
Creed staying in the pocket, Max. Moving, not running.
奎迪對惠勒如影隨形 持續出擊 不躲也不停
Come on, now! Hands up! Hands up!
再加把勁 出拳
These two men are really going at it.
兩位拳手真的都拼盡了全力
Tell him, Donnie!
幹掉他 多尼
Another left hook drives Wheeler back.
又一記左勾拳 惠勒連連後退
Come on, baby!
加油 兄弟
That was a sneaky little uppercut on the inside,
奎迪冷不丁從空隙裏揮出一記上勾拳
and Wheeler's hurt by that, Roy.
惠勒受到了重創 羅伊
Yeah, that wobbled his legs pretty bad.
沒錯 他的腿抖得厲害
- Another big shot! - Hold him, hold him, hold him!
- 又是一記重擊 - 出拳 出拳
Creed has him in trouble, Max.
奎迪壓制住惠勒了 馬克斯
Wheeler's doing what he can...
惠勒正在奮力抵抗 但是
Wheeler is down!
惠勒倒下了
Wheeler has hit the canvas!
惠勒倒在了拳台上
Now stay there, boy!
你就趴著吧 小子
Creed taught you!
我奎迪才是贏家
Come and give me my keys!
讓他把車鑰匙還我
Get up! Come on, baby!
快起來 加油 兄弟
Get up, get up!
快起來
- Wheeler, trying to get up. - One!
- 惠勒掙扎著想站起來 - 一
- Stay down! - Two!
- 趴著吧 - 二
I don't know if he makes this count, Roy.
但不知能否趕在倒計時結束前起身
Three!
三
Four!
四
Five!
五
Six!
六
Seven!
七
Eight!
八
Nine!
九
That's it. That's it.
結束了
And it's over, Max.
比賽結束了 馬克斯
No way! Adonis Creed...
難以置信 阿多尼斯·奎迪
Give me my keys!
還我車鑰匙
...is the heavyweight champion of the world.
他登上了世界重量級拳賽的拳王寶座
You know what you just did?
你知道你成拳王了嗎
Yeah.
知道
Baby, you know what just happened?
寶貝 你知道發生什麼了嗎
When you think of where this kid has come from,
大家可以想想這個年輕人的出身
the most unlikely beginning for a fighter, Roy.
以他的起點是不可能當上拳手的 羅伊
Growing up the way he did
按照他的成長路徑
to make it to the top of boxing in this way...
他能這樣一步一步地登上拳王寶座
It's unprecedented!
可以說是史無前例
Creed! Creed! Creed!
奎迪 奎迪 奎迪
It's one thing to be the number one contender.
成為頭號拳王競爭者是一回事
It's a whole other thing to be champion.
真正成為拳王則完全是另一回事
This is the first step to building a legacy of his own,
今晚就是他稱霸拳壇 續寫拳王傳奇的第一步
and I can hardly wait to see what's next for Adonis Creed.
我已經迫不及待想看到阿多尼斯·奎迪 會有怎樣的未來
I mean, what do you think?
這個怎麼樣
That's...
這
That is beautiful.
這真是太漂亮了
- Right? - Yeah.
- 是吧 - 是
But we gotta hurry up.
我們得快點
I mean, she's about to get out the shower any second.
她隨時都可能洗完澡出來的
Yo, Donnie, why didn't you tell me about this before?
多尼 你之前怎麼都不告訴我呢
I didn't know if I was gonna win.
我又不確定能不能贏
What's that got to do with it?
和能不能贏有什麼關係
I don't know.
我說不好
Look, just tell me what I should do.
好了 你教我怎麼做
You get down on one knee.
你得單膝下跪
People still do that shit?
這一套還沒過時嗎
You can always send her a text.
發短信求婚也不是不行
Come on, Unc, I'm being serious, all right?
拜託 大叔 我是認真的 好嗎
I mean, what did you say?
你怎麼求婚的
- To Adrian? - Yeah.
- 跟艾德裏安嗎 - 對
It was a long time ago.
那是很久前的事了
We were at the zoo. It was winter. It was snowing.
我們去了動物園 那時還是冬天 下著雪
Everything smelled fresh.
空氣非常清新
There was this tiger. He had snow on its back.
有一隻老虎 背上落著一層雪花
- And he's walking in the background. - Okay, I get it. I get it.
- 它在遠處走來走去 然後 - 好了 我知道了
Just tell me what you said.
你就說你怎麼求的
Well, I was getting to that part.
我正要說這段呢
What I said is...
我當時就問她
I asked if she would not mind marrying me very much,
會不會特別反感跟我結婚
which is kind of a dumb way of saying she's my world,
我這麼說就等於含蓄地暗示 她是我的一切
and she made me better than I deserved to be.
是她拯救了那個原本會墮落的我
You know?
你懂的
Yeah.
是這樣
Listen, why don't you just turn off your brain
聽著 你就乾脆別想太多
and let your heart do the talking.
把真正的心裏話說給她聽
Click.
敞開心門
You'll do good.
你會如願的
- Turn my brain off? - Yeah.
- 不用想太多 - 沒錯
- Okay. - Mmm-hmm.
好的
- All right.
好的 明白
All right, I'm on it.
沒錯 我知道了
- Hey, Unc. - Mmm.
大叔
You good?
你沒事吧
Yeah, real good. Thank you.
沒事 好著呢 謝謝
- Great. - All right.
- 真的挺好 - 好
Will you marry me?
嫁給我 好嗎
Listen, B.
聽著 比安
I know we've been dating for a few years now,
我們已然在一起好幾年了
and it's just something about us that just click.
而且我們倆相處得挺合拍
I don't know how to explain it,
我不知道怎麼解釋 可是
but the feeling I get when you're by my side is a feeling
你陪在我身邊的那種感覺其實讓我
that I can't live without.
已經戒不掉了
I know I sound crazy, but, look, I guess what I'm trying to say is...
我知道很瘋狂 但是我就是想跟你說 那個
Will you marry me?
嫁給我 好嗎
I'm still hungry, babe,
我還是很餓 寶貝
I don't know why.
也不知道怎麼了
Are you for real, D?
你認真的嗎
Yeah, I'm for real.
是 我很認真
No, stop playin'.
別鬧 不要耍我
I ain't playin'.
我沒耍你
You didn't hear any of that?
你沒聽見 對吧
None of what?
聽見什麼
None of what, D?
我沒聽見什麼
What did you say?
你說了什麼
Nothing that you don't already know.
你已經知道我說什麼了
Remind me.
提醒我一下
I said that I love you,
我說了我很愛你
and that I need you.
還有我很需要你
D, do you know what you're doing right now?
多尼 你知道你在幹什麼嗎
I mean, yeah, kind of.
我算是知道吧
What do you mean, "kind of"?
什麼叫算是
Babe!
寶貝
I mean...
我是
To keep it real with you, B,
想跟你說心裏話
you're the only person
我只想跟你
I wanna share my moments with.
分享我人生的點點滴滴
So, Bianca Taylor,
所以 比安卡·泰勒
will you marry me?
嫁給我好嗎
Yo.
嗯
- "Yo"? Is that a yes? - Yes.
- 那這算答應了 - 是的
It's yes?
這算答應了麼
Yes!
是的
Yeah.
好
Viktor.
維克托
Our boy's looking good.
這小子狀態不錯啊
I'm sure you heard the good news.
好消息都聽說了吧
It's time.
機會來了
You ever thought about going back to LA?
你有沒有想過搬回洛杉磯去住
Please, you're a Philly girl.
算了吧 你可是費城人
Yeah, I guess,
話是這麼說 但是
but it'd be nice to have more space.
那邊有更大的發展空甸
And your mom's out there...
再說 你媽媽也在那邊
And them labels, too.
還有不少唱片公司
Could help me get my music out to more people.
我有機會讓更多人聽到我的音樂
I don't know, I feel like I've done everything I could in Philly, you know?
我總感覺我在費城發展到頭了 你懂吧
Time ain't exactly on my side, you know?
我能做音樂的時間也不多了
What about Rocky?
那洛奇怎麼辦
Rocky has his life, D.
洛奇有自己的生活啊
We gotta start ours.
我們也得考慮未來
It's a cold one today, Adrian, that's for sure.
今天可真冷啊 艾德裏安 真的很冷
I tried calling our son Bobby a few times.
我之前給咱們的兒子博比打了幾次電話
But I'd hang up every time he was about to pick up
但是每次他要接的時候我就又給掛了
because, to tell you the truth, I didn't know what to say to him.
因為說實話我不知道要說什麼
What if he's moving on,
要是他新生活過得好好的
and I'm like this chunk of yesterday trying to be today?
我以前沒管過也 現在卻去插一腳
I just don't fit in.
也挺不合適的
I mean, what am I supposed to do?
可我到底該怎麼做呢
Knock on his door and say, "Hey, how you doing?
敲開他的門直接說 你好嗎
"What's it been, a lot of years?" I don't know.
咱們有多久沒見了 這不太好吧
I miss you.
我想你
You've been hype ever since you got this jawn.
自從你贏回這輛車就一直很興奮啊
What are you talking about?
你說什麼呢
That smile right there.
就是這個笑容
You're cheezin'.
都笑開花了
It's the only thing my pops left me.
我爸就留給我這麼輛車
I mean, that and these hands.
當然了 還有拳頭
- You never told me that. - Yeah.
- 你沒說過這事 - 是
What's up with you and these secrets, Don?
你怎麼會藏著這麼多秘密啊 多尼
How're you doing? All right, all right.
你怎麼樣 好
But look at this, here.
看這邊
- How you doing? - Hey.
- 你怎麼樣 - 你好
- Hey, Isabelle. - Hey, Rock.
- 伊莎貝爾 - 洛奇
Hey, listen. Some big guy's sitting over there, waiting for you.
聽著 那邊坐了一個大塊頭 一直在等你
He said you'll know who he is.
他說你知道他是誰
Yo, champ.
拳王
You gotta take that fight, man. Shut this dude up.
你得跟這傢伙打 兄弟 打得他心服口服
No, Wheeler still talking shit?
不會吧 惠勒還沒認輸嗎
It's a little early for a rematch, bro.
還不到再跟他打的時候
Hey, turn the TV up.
電視聲開大點
...and the tragic history that connects them.
拳壇歷史上的悲劇又將兩代人扯到了一起
That you?
是你
Nice pictures.
這些照片不錯
Yeah, they're okay.
是 都照得挺好
No pictures of me.
但是裏面沒有我的
No, there's no pictures of that.
沒有 我這兒確實沒你的照片
Why are you in Philly?
你怎麼在費城
You don't know?
你不知道嗎
Ukrainian boxer Viktor Drago appeared today in Philadelphia
維克托·德拉龍向阿多尼斯·奎迪宣戰
to issue a very public challenge
於今日現身美國費城
to recently crowned heavyweight champion Adonis Creed.
公開宣佈自己要挑戰最近加冕的世界重量級拳王阿多尼斯·奎迪
A press conference was held earlier by boxing promoter Buddy Marcelle.
拳賽經紀人巴迪·瑪塞勒日前為此召開了記者招待會
We came all the way to Philly to let you know it's serious.
我們專程來費城就是告訴你這不是開玩笑
Now, this man here, he ain't no Danny Wheeler.
我身邊這位可不像丹尼·惠勒那麼弱
And let's be honest, Creed fought him three years too late, anyway.
而且說實話奎迪是在惠勒巔峰期過了三年後才贏的
Easy match.
贏了不稀奇
People in this country love you.
你在這個國家備受愛戴
But Russia,
但在我的國家
no one touch Drago name.
德拉戈之名無可撼動
Everything changed that night.
可是那一晚的比賽改變了一切
Look, you know, that's like
你看 那件事都已經
a million years ago.
已經是八百年前的事了
Like yesterday to me.
可對我卻仿如昨日
So, you came all the way over here to tell me that?
你大老遠到我這兒來就想說這個嗎
It's no coincidence that Ivan Drago's son shows up
阿波羅·奎迪的兒子剛剛捧回金腰帶
right after Apollo Creed's son claims the belt.
伊凡·德拉戈的兒子就出現 這恐怕不是巧合
This is Creed versus Drago.
這是奎迪家對德拉戈家的復仇之戰
This is the fight the whole world wants to see.
也是一場萬眾期待的世紀之戰
And this is the fight he should take.
阿多尼斯理應接受挑戰
Unless he's afraid of history repeating itself.
除非他害怕歷史會在自己身上重演
That history being the infamous 1985 match
這段歷史指的是1985年那場殘酷的比賽
in which boxing legend Apollo Creed was killed by Russian fighter
傳奇拳手阿波羅·奎迪在比賽中
Ivan Drago.
死在了俄羅斯拳手伊凡·德拉戈的拳下
Apollo's trainer Rocky Balboa was heavily criticized
而阿波羅的教練洛奇·巴爾博亞
for failing to stop that fight.
也因未能及時叫停比賽 遭受到了巨大的譴責
D. Baby.
多尼 寶貝
It's a publicity stunt.
他們就是在炒作而己
Don't worry about that.
這種事別放心上
And let's not forget,
後來
later that year, Balboa defeated Drago in his own backyard, Russia.
在同一年 德拉戈又被巴爾博亞所擊敗 而且是在自己的家門口 俄羅斯
Because of you, I lose everything.
就因為你 我失去了一切
Country.
祖國
Respect.
我的尊嚴
Wife.
還有妻子
You ever see stray dogs in Ukraine?
你有沒有見過烏克蘭的流浪狗
They go for days with no food.
它們日日夜夜忍饑挨餓
People spit on them. They have nothing.
還要受人類唾棄 一無所有
No home.
無家可歸
Only will to survive, to fight.
它們一心只想著生存 還有戰鬥
I have son.
我有個兒子
All he knows
他只會用拳頭
is this.
拚命
My son will break your boy.
我的兒子會打敗你的徒弟
Been a long day.
我有點累了
I think we're done here.
就說到這兒吧
Because around here we put strays away.
我們這裏可不會讓流浪狗到處亂吠
It's good picture.
這張照片不錯
I kind of figured you'd be here.
我就猜到你會在這裏
You know, I tried calling and calling, but nobody picked up or anything.
我之前不停地給你打電話 可是一直就沒有人接
Kind of early to be training, don't you think, after a fight?
你不覺得剛比完就訓練 有點操之過急嗎
Just trying to clear my head.
我是想醒醒腦
I get that.
我明白了
Cheaper than a shrink, that's for sure.
這反正比看心理醫生便宜
Hey, Don, come on. I heard what's going on.
多尼 好了 我知道發生了什麼
But you can't let them get inside.
但是你不能讓他們擾亂你
But I know how you're feeling.
不過你的心情我也理解
- Oh, do you? - Yeah, I do.
- 是嗎 - 真的 我懂
What happened a long time ago, that ain't got nothing to do with you.
那些恩怨都過去那麼久 跟你一點關係都沒有
Listen, that fight is what Apollo wanted, all right?
聽著 那場比賽是阿波羅自己想打的 懂嗎
It shouldn't have happened.
雖然不該發生
But it did.
可這是命
And you gotta let it go.
別再糾結了
Come on.
放下
You've seen him fight, though?
你看過維克托比賽嗎
I've seen him on sports TV and stuff like that.
我在體育頻道和其他節目上看過
He's big, but he's raw.
他很壯 可惜太嫩
He ain't no mean machine like you are, that's for sure.
他可打不過你這麼老到的拳手 我敢肯定
You know what?
這樣好了
I'm gonna cheer you up, 'cause today's gonna be your lucky day.
我幫你振作一下 今天你算是撞大運了
Christmas just came early for you,
提前給你個聖誕禮物吧
'cause I'm gonna hold the bag, lucky guy.
我來親自為你扶沙袋 幸運的小子
- No, you're the one who's lucky. - How's that?
- 不 幸運的是你 - 為什麼
'Cause I'm gonna let you hold the bag for me.
因為我讓你有幸為我扶沙袋
Yo.
不錯
That's it. That's better.
這一拳更好
Creed taking major hits. This could be over soon.
奎迪挨了好幾拳 看來比賽快結束了
Creed is down! And he could be badly hurt.
奎迪倒地了 而且他可能受了重傷
Apollo on the floor looking unresponsive.
阿波羅倒在地上沒有反應了
This doesn't look good.
情況似乎不妙
There is no movement.
他完全不能動了
♪ Glitter in my eyes And I was young
我年少時 眸中燦若晨星
♪ Know what they say I ran away from home
他們說我曾經桀驁不馴
♪ I thank you I learned the world
謝謝你讓我瞭解這個世界
♪ They think I'm a broken girl
他們說我的心早已支離破碎
♪ I think I'm in love with lost
我只是喜歡這種迷失的感覺
Amazing voice.
她聲音真棒
♪ My heart cracked But at least it's touched ♪
我心已碎 但起碼它跳動過
Sorry for the theatrics.
抱歉 我在媒體前有點誇張
But people like a good show.
可大家就愛看好戲
That was a grimy move, brah.
你這招太賤了 夥計
Ain't nothing personal.
我不是針對你
Can't say I'm proud of what our sport's become,
我對拳壇的現狀是沒什麼自豪感
but that's the game.
可世道就是這樣
Call it whatever you want.
隨便你怎麼說
Sounds to me like you just trying to get paid.
反正在我聽來你就是想賺錢
The money is a side effect.
錢只是順便賺來的
"The Rumble in the Jungle" didn't just manifest itself.
阿里那場世紀大戰的盛況可不是憑空出現的
Somebody had to make it happen.
得有人組織策劃
Will it into existence.
把願望變成現實
Oh, yeah, that's supposed to be you, huh?
你要當這人 是吧
You see anybody else standing here with a care in their heart?
你在這圈子還見過誰是真正關心拳手利益的
I want the same thing you want.
你我想要的都一樣
Yeah? What's that?
是嗎 我要什麼
In the history of boxing,
在拳壇的歷史上
there have been 77 heavyweight champions.
一共出現過77位重量級的拳王
You know that?
這你知道嗎
But how many do you think they know?
你覺得大眾認識幾個
Four?
四個嗎
Five?
五個嗎
The belt ain't enough.
有金腰帶不夠
You need a narrative. Something that sticks to the ribs.
你得有故事 能讓大眾長時間津津樂道
Your dad, he knew that.
你父親 他就很懂
Do yourself a favor, brah,
我勸你還是好自為之
and quit while you ahead.
趁早收手別惹禍
Self-preservation.
你想明哲保身
At least you got that over your old man.
至少這點你比你老爸強
That must be Rocky whispering in your ear.
是洛奇吹耳邊風攔著你吧
I'm serious.
我是認真的
Amazing voice.
她的聲音真不錯
Yo, thank you, Fillmore.
謝謝 菲爾莫爾
For real though, thank you.
非常感謝
How you doing, kid?
你怎麼樣 小子
We gotta talk.
我們談談吧
Let's take a walk and get some air.
那咱們散散步 透透氣
Okay? Kind of stuffy in here.
好嗎 這屋裏有點悶
Look at that light.
你看那燈
That thing's been broken for a couple of years.
那玩意兒已經壞了好幾年了
It's driving me crazy.
我都要煩死了
City won't fix it or nothing.
市政局不給修 也不理我
What good is a light
燈亮不起來
that don't light, right?
那還有什麼用啊
Kind of funny, but it's stupid, too.
這事挺逗 但這麼一看 也夠傻的
I gotta take the fight.
我要接受挑戰
Why?
為什麼
These dudes killed my pops.
那兩個混蛋殺了我爸
Now they're parading around, talking shit?
結果現在還招搖過市胡說八道
I can't let that slide.
我不能放過他們
I'm the champ, right?
我是拳王對嗎
Yeah.
對
So I ain't got a choice.
所以我別無選擇
Choice?
選擇嗎
That's the same thing your father said,
你爸爸當年也說過這句話
and he died right here, in my hands.
然後我就眼睜睜看著他死在我懷裏
Look what his choice put your mother through.
你看看他的選擇讓你媽媽受了多少苦
You don't wanna really bring all that stuff up again, do you, kid?
你不想這種事落在比安卡頭上吧 孩子
I thought you would get it.
我以為你能懂
If I don't take this fight, I gotta live with it right now.
如果我不接受挑戰 我現在就得受著煎熬
That kid was raised in hate, you know what I'm talking about?
那孩子是在仇恨裏長大的 你懂我的意思嗎
You weren't. Don't do it.
而你不是 別去報仇
- But you did. - It's different.
- 可你去了 - 那不一樣
It was different?
哪裏不一樣
It's a lot different.
很多地方不一樣
I was supposed to be in there with Drago that night
其實那晚跟德拉戈對打的應該是我
and not your father.
而不是你爸爸
And I could've thrown in the towel,
我本來可以扔毛巾認輸
but I didn't.
可我沒有
And I gotta live with that.
我活該抱憾終身
And when I did get in that ring,
後來我去找德拉戈報仇
that guy broke things in me
他的慾望摧毀了我的信念
that ain't never been fixed.
這輩子都無法復原
It's not worth it.
這麼做不值
Not at all.
一點也不值
Why do you wanna fight?
你為什麼想跟他打
What are you talking about? I just told you why.
什麼意思 我剛剛都告訴你了
No, you didn't, Donnie.
不 你沒有 多尼
Why do you wanna fight?
你到底為什麼想跟他打
I get why they wanna fight you.
我知道他們為什麼跟你打
I know what they're fighting for.
我知道他們父子想要什麼
What about you?
那你呢
Listen to me, you got everything to lose.
聽我說 你的人生什麼都輸不起
He's got nothing to lose.
而他沒什麼可輸的
When a fighter ain't got nothing to lose, he's dangerous.
如果一個拳手沒什麼可輸的 那就太可怕了
I'm dangerous!
我也不是吃素的
You think I'm gonna lose.
你覺得我打不過他
I didn't say that.
我沒這麼說
Same guy that said he ain't have enough experience.
你不是說過他沒什麼經驗嗎
- Raw, right? - Yeah.
- 太嫩 對吧 - 對
But you don't think I could beat him.
可你還是覺得我打不過他
- Is that what you're trying to say? - No.
你是想說這個嗎
No, that's not what I'm saying.
不 我想說的不是這個
I'm saying I'm not gonna be here forever.
我是說我不可能永遠在這兒守著你
And what's that supposed to mean?
你這話是什麼意思
That means you gotta do some smart thinking.
意思就是你得想清楚 別犯傻
Oh, you wanna talk about smart decisions, Rock?
你覺得你守著我是犯傻嗎 洛奇
You in this house all alone.
你孤零零住在這屋裏
Who been taking care of you? Me.
誰照顧你的 我
I've been here for you!
我一直守著你
Who else you got?
還有誰這麼對你
Listen.
聽著
I'm taking this fight with or without you.
不管你支不支持 我都會應戰
It's gotta be without.
我沒法支持你
I can't do it.
我做不到
So that's it?
就這樣了嗎
You walkin' out on me?
你就這麼不管我了
At least you ain't gotta worry about throwing in the towel this time.
這次你倒是不用糾結要不要再認輸了
Yeah.
是啊
D, are you okay?
多尼 你還好嗎
Rocky, man.
洛奇那傢伙
Rocky what?
洛奇怎麼了
He ain't training me for the fight.
他拒絕幫我備戰
Wait, you're taking the fight?
等等 你要接受挑戰嗎
All the shit that we've been through.
我們經歷了那麼多
He gonna leave me high and dry. That's bullshit!
他說不管我就不管我了 簡直混蛋
I took care of him when he had cancer.
他得癌癥都是我在照顧
He could've been dead, B.
不然他早死了 比安
I'm sure he has his reasons.
洛奇肯定有他的理由
Oh, yeah? Like what?
是嗎 什麼理由
Like what?
什麼理由
I don't need him.
我才不用他管
I love it.
我喜歡這裏
Me, too.
我也是
I want just a little piece of that room for a studio.
我想在那間屋子辟一個小角落 佈置工作間
That works. It's all you.
沒問題 隨便佈置
What's wrong?
怎麼了
I don't know. Maybe I'm just a little tired from the flight.
說不清可 能是一路飛過來有點累了
I'm okay.
沒事的
We don't have to go out.
那我們就別出去了
We can just stay in, order some food.
不如待在家裏 叫個外賣
Hmm. No, baby, you have to tell her.
不 寶貝 你得見見你媽媽
So, how's the music?
你還在唱歌嗎
Oh, Donnie didn't tell you?
多尼沒告訴你嗎
D?
多尼
Uh... I forgot.
我忘了
Oh. Yeah, I signed.
忘了 我簽了公司
Hello.
真的嗎
Yeah, it's great. The record label really hit the ground running, too.
真的 特別棒 公司也開始給我籌備發唱片了
I'm up for festivals this summer.
今年夏天我就要去音樂節演出了
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
- 真是恭喜你 - 謝謝
So, how's Rocky?
洛奇怎麼樣了
He didn't wanna make the trip?
他不想過來玩玩嗎
Nah, Ma, you know how he is
媽 你也知道他這個人
with the traveling.
他不愛出遠門
Okay, Ma.
好吧 媽
I'm sure you already guessed it, but...
你肯定已經猜到了 不過
Oh, yeah.
沒錯
I already know.
我早就猜到了
All the salt,
這麼愛吃咸的
shiny hair,
頭髮也亮
glowing skin.
簡直容光煥發
How far along are you?
懷孕幾個月了
Ma, you think...
媽 你是以為
You think...
你以為
No.
不是
We couldn't even... No.
我們都還沒 不是的 這真是
Your mamma's got jokes, okay.
媽喜歡開玩笑
No, I'm not.
不 我沒懷孕
All right.
好吧
- What's it say? - D, don't touch it.
- 結果是什麼 - 多尼 別碰
No, I don't care if you peed on it. I just want to see...
我又不在乎它上面有沒有尿 我只想看看
I don't want you to mess it up.
我是讓你別亂動它
What's it say?
怎麼樣
It's two blue lines.
有兩條藍線
Two blue lines? What does that mean?
兩條藍線 是什麼意思
Two blue lines.
兩條藍線
Maybe it's broke.
老天 它可能是壞了
That's crazy.
這不可能
Hell, I don't know, D.
我很猶豫 多尼
Baby, I don't know.
寶貝 我很猶豫
You did say you always wanted kids, right?
你一直都想要孩子 對吧
Yeah, but I didn't say so soon.
對 可我沒想這麼早要
I don't know if I'm...
我不知道我..我們
If we are ready.
準備好了嗎
Let's get ready, then.
現在準備也不遲
Yeah.
對
Did she tell her family yet?
她告訴家裏人了嗎
She's, uh, on the phone with her aunt right now.
她現在就和她姑媽打電話呢
Oh, that Bianca's a good one.
比安卡可是好姑娘
Why she agreed to marry you, I do not know.
她怎麼會答應嫁給你呢 我是真想不通
I don't know either.
其實我也想不通
Oh, it's good to have you home.
你們回來可真好
Ma, um...
媽
That fight
那場比賽
between me
你知道
and Ivan Drago's son...
對手是伊凡·德拉戈的兒子
I'm gonna take it.
我想接受挑戰
Okay.
好吧
That's it?
就這樣嗎
What else is there to say?
那你還想聽我說什麼
So, that doesn't bother you?
難道你不擔心嗎
Oh, you think this doesn't bother me?
我怎麼可能不擔心
You're a grown man.
可你是成年人
It doesn't matter what I or anyone else thinks.
我和別人怎麼想對你來說都不重要
You wanna fight this man, that's your business.
你想跟那個人打是你的事情
You don't need my blessings.
你又不需要我祝福你
You clearly don't have Rocky's.
洛奇不也沒祝福你嗎
Rocky don't get it.
洛奇理解不了
It wasn't his dad.
死的不是他爸
It changed my life.
我的人生都改寫了
Your life.
還有你的人生
You're telling me you don't miss him?
你難道不想爸爸嗎
Excuse me!
你說什麼
Do not try to make this about me.
別把這事扯到我頭上
And don't pretend that it's about your father.
也別拿你爸爸給自己當借口
You became the world champion without him.
沒有你爸 你也成了世界拳王
Then why don't I feel like it?
可我好像不想當拳王
If your father was here, he would tell you he didn't feel like it either.
要是你爸還活著 他也會告訴你 他不想當拳王
But he's not.
可他不在了
I just hope you'll be here for your child.
我只希望你能陪自己的孩子成長
Why are you so stupid?
你怎麼這麼傻
Stop.
別鬧
D, you're tickling me with that fake beard.
多尼 你那兩撮鬍渣撓得我癢癢
The disrespect.
敢這麼說我鬍子
Why don't you sing for us?
給我和寶寶唱首歌
No, I am not your jukebox.
不 我可不是你的點唱機
I'm not gonna be walking around here, barefoot and pregnant,
也別指望我光著腳 挺著大肚子
making you sandwiches either.
還給你做什麼三明治吃
Did you hear that? No sandwiches, no singing.
你聽聽 不給做三明治 也不給唱歌
Your mamma just hating on us.
你媽媽對咱倆真狠心
Did you hear that?
你聽見了嗎
What if the baby can't, D?
要是寶寶隨我怎麼辦
Can't what?
什麼隨你
Can't hear.
失聰
You know it can be hereditary, right?
你知道這病可能遺傳吧
Everything is gonna be fine.
一切都會好起來的
I promise.
我保證
People are gonna be all over this fight.
這場比賽的關注度一定非常高
It got a lot of bad history, man.
你們背後可是血海深仇啊 老弟
Everything.
糾葛太多
Your dad.
你老爸
And yours, too.
還有你爸啊
Don't forget that he trained him.
你爸當過我爸的教練
I know why you didn't train me before.
我明白你之前為什麼不教我了
I wasn't ready.
我當時不夠格
You was right.
維克托夠格
Yeah, but this is different.
是 可這次不一樣
Drago's kid...
德拉戈的兒子
Big.
塊頭大
Fast.
速度快
Strong.
很強壯
Unorthodox.
路子還野得很
He's a monster, boy.
他是個怪物 小子
It's a balanced breakfast over there.
這個人身上就沒有短板
You think you ready for all that?
你覺得你對付得了嗎
I gotta be.
我必須對付他
But if you ain't gonna do it for me,
你不願意幫我沒關係
at least do it for them.
就當是為他們
Think about it.
好好考慮一下
Beat what they couldn't beat.
就當替他們了卻遺憾
Change the way they were remembered.
也能洗刷平反他們的名聲
This is our chance to rewrite history.
抓住這個機會 我們就能改寫歷史
Our history.
我們的歷史
His record might be light, but, believe me,
他的戰績也許不怎麼樣 但是相信我
he ain't no undercard.
他絕對不好對付
So, you gotta be with me.
你一定得聽我的
I'm right here.
都聽你的
We'll see.
試試吧
Creed versus Drago.
奎迪對戰德拉戈
That means something.
這場決鬥有特殊的意義
Did that factor into your decision to take this fight?
你決定應戰是因為你們兩家的歷史淵源嗎
I mean, you can't say Creed without Drago, right?
提到奎迪就不得不說德拉戈 對吧
This is what y'all want.
你們想看我們打
It's what everyone wants.
大家都想看我們打
Also, can't help but to notice,
還有件事很難不注意到
who won't be in your corner this time around.
那就是這次你的團隊裏缺了一個人
Rocky's taking some family time.
洛奇在享受天倫之樂
But Duke's got me.
我還有小公爵
His father taught my father everything he knows.
他父親把畢生絕技都傳給我爸爸了
Speed, D. That's how we gonna beat him.
快 多尼 速度才是關鍵
Technique, speed...
注重技巧 加強速度
I'm confident he'll have me ready for this fight.
我相信他能幫我做好備戰
And knowing what happened between your father and Drago,
那想到你父親和德拉戈當年的仇恨與糾葛
you must have some worry.
想必你也有一些擔心吧
What would I be afraid of?
我有什麼可擔心的
I'm a fighter. This is what I do, right?
誰想嘗嘗我的厲害 我是拳手 就得打拳 對嗎
Who the champ?
誰是拳王
It's who I am.
這就是我
Looking good!
看起來不錯
Creed! Creed! Creed!
奎迪
You're much smaller than your father.
你可比你爸矮小多了
Don't you talk about my pop.
你敢提我爸
Hey, we could do this right here, bro.
你想現在打也可以
- Step up here! - D!
- 上來啊 - 多尼
He can't help you no more!
你爸明天就幫不了你了
You hear me? He can't help behind that ring!
聽見了嗎 你能躲在在台下了
You stand there. All you're doing is talking, homie.
你站在拳台上也就能耍耍嘴皮子了
Your pops can't protect you, you feel me?
你爸保護不了你了 懂嗎
Don't talk about my father! Don't turn your back on me!
你們不准提我爸 你們有膽就別走
You in my house, homie!
這是我的主場 老兄
Make sure they hold them down. We're in the dressing room.
一定要攔住他們 我們在更衣室
Jim Lampley here, along with Roy Jones.
我是吉姆·蘭普利 我旁邊是羅伊·瓊斯
We're moments away from tonight's main event.
今晚的大戰馬上就要拉開帷幕了
Jim, I would have never thought in a million years
吉姆 我真的做夢也想不到
I'd witness another Creed versus Drago fight.
我們竟然能看到奎迪家和德拉戈家下一代的對戰
Well, get ready, Roy. Drago makes his way to the ring.
是 好戲開演了 羅伊 小德拉戈正向拳台走來
His father leads the way through the hostile crowd.
他的父親正帶著他 穿過敵意洶涌的人潮
You can feel the energy. I'm sure Creed does.
這是民心所向的力量 奎迪肯定也感覺到了
He has a big advantage with the fans in his corner.
觀眾們都支持他
Stay focused. You're at home, baby. Focus is the key.
集中精神 這是你的主場 兄弟 一定不能分心
Given Drago's size and style,
考慮到德拉戈的體格和打鬥風格
he'll look to use his power to counter Creed's speed.
他可能會用力量來壓制奎迪的速度
Remember why we're here, man.
你知道我們都支持你
I'm the champ.
我是拳王
Adonis Creed making a grand entrance tonight.
阿多尼斯·奎迪今晚的閃亮登場引發了全場矚目
Like his father, Creed is ever the showman,
這點像他的父親 奎迪家的人都很張揚
and is energizing the crowd.
能讓觀眾為他們瘋狂
Creed is letting Drago know exactly who this arena belongs to.
奎迪是想讓德拉戈看看 誰才是這拳台的主宰
It all feels so Shakespearean.
這一切就彷彿是莎士比亞筆下的情節
Two sons, raised a world apart, yet inexorably linked by tragedy.
兩位男孩 出身可謂是雲泥之別 卻被一樁悲情的往事綁在了一起
Now, gentlemen,
好了 先生們
I went over the rules in the dressing room.
我在更衣室已經重申過比賽規則了
I wanna caution you to keep this fight clean at all times.
我要提醒兩位 需時刻遵守規則 公平競賽
Protect yourself at all times.
也需時刻保護好人身安全
And what I say, you must obey.
請兩位務必聽從我說的話
Good luck. Touch gloves.
祝你們好運 碰拳套吧
Touch gloves.
請碰拳套
Creed fights without longtime trainer Rocky Balboa.
奎迪的教練洛奇·巴爾博亞並未前來觀戰
Interesting to see how Duke manages the corner
小公爵如何指導奎迪摒棄世仇的影響
with so much bad blood between the fighters.
好好發揮 將是一大看點
Look at him.
看著他
He think he gonna run straight through you.
想像他徑直朝你衝過來
- You show him what's up. - Yeah.
- 給他點顏色看看 好嗎 - 好
This is your house, all right?
這是你的主場 懂嗎
- It's my house. - Let's go, baby.
- 這是我的主場 - 上吧 兄弟
Box!
開始
And we're underway.
比賽正式開始了
If all goes according to form,
單從競技狀態上來看
Creed is seen as the more versatile boxer, quicker...
奎迪被公認是靈活的全能型拳手
Yeah, baby, throw that jab! Let it rip!
對 用刺拳 逼出破綻
Drago is trying to land something big.
德拉戈 現在也要開始發力了
Dig, dig.
重錘 重錘
Downstairs.
攻擊下盤
Creed connects with a couple of body shots.
奎迪連續出拳擊中對方身體
And a right hand upstairs for Creed.
奎迪向上揮出一記右勾拳
Drago hasn't thrown a meaningful punch yet.
德拉戈按兵不動 還未發動有效攻擊
And another right hand for Creed.
奎迪又是一記右勾拳
Creed blocked that punch
奎迪擋住了這一拳
and still it knocked him back into the ropes.
不過他還是被逼到了場邊
Yeah, we good.
有兩下子
Creed doesn't like that, Jim.
奎迪有點生氣了 吉姆
Don't be stupid, kid. He's baiting you.
別被騙了 小子 他是想激怒你
Creed pressing now, angrily rushes forward with a volley of punches.
奎迪步步緊逼 帶著怒氣發起了猛攻
He's pulling you in.
他要你近身
A huge left hook by Drago!
德拉戈這記左勾拳真是穩准狠
- Come on, kid. - Creed shaken up by that punch.
- 奎迪似乎被這一拳打懵了 - 加油
Clear your head.
別有雜念
Creed commands the center of the ring,
奎迪佔據了拳台中央
but there's a hard body shot to the ribs.
卻被狼狽地狠狠打中了左肋
And another one on the other side.
現在右側也受到了重擊
What you doing, baby? What you doing, D?
你怎麼了 兄弟 振作點 多尼
And a right hand by Drago that knocks Creed's head back.
德拉戈揮出一記右勾拳 打得奎迪仰過頭去
Creed can feel the power behind those punches.
奎迪感受到了對手拳頭的力量
And now Drago is on the attack.
現在德拉戈始正式反擊了
Jab out, jab out, jab out. Hands up, let's go!
出拳 舉起拳頭 繼續
Drago's stalking him along the ropes.
德拉戈沿著圍繩步步為營
Get off the ropes, D!
別靠近圍繩 多尼
Out the corner!
別進角落
No, D! Out the corner, out the corner!
不 多尼 離開角落
Hard right hand by Drago, and Creed is shaken
德拉戈猛地揮出右拳 奎迪被打都站不穩了
as the first round comes to a close.
至此比賽的第一回合結束
I think most watching at home are a little surprised
許多不在現場觀賽的觀眾 可能會有點驚訝
by how impressive Viktor Drago has looked
因為維克托·德拉戈
in these opening minutes of the fight.
在剛開場的這幾分鐘裏表現得相當令人驚艷
With the history these men share,
兩位拳手積怨已久
Duke may have his hands full keeping Creed
小公爵光是要讓奎迪免受情緒干擾
from letting his emotions get the best of him.
恐怕就已經費盡心力了
What you doing, D?
怎麼回事 多尼
- You need to stick with the game plan. - I know, I know.
- 你得按照咱們的計劃來 - 我知道
Stay off the line. Take your angles. You ain't taking your angles.
別靠近圍繩 調整角度 你沒掌握好角度
I know!
我知道
If he throws you a left hook...
如果他對你出左勾拳 就得小心
Come on, man, hold the phone on that.
你再這樣擋他啊
- You think I don't know that shit? - Well, if you know it,
- 怎麼擋我會不知道 - 既然你知道
do it!
那就擋啊
And now, as we prepare for round two, this crowd is still buzzing
現在第二回合即將開始 觀眾席上還是一片沸騰
from the vicious rally that Drago brought forth in the last minute
在第一回合的對決中 德拉戈揮舞的重拳之下是深沉的敵意
of round number one.
他發起的連續攻擊 竟然在最後一刻
Come out smart.
清醒點 別犯傻
Got Creed in serious trouble as the round came to a close.
將奎迪打得全無招架之力
Box!
開始
And now, round two begins.
現在第二回合開始了
And Drago comes out throwing, wasting no time.
德拉戈一上來就發動了猛烈進攻 絲毫沒有遲疑
- Get off the ropes! - And Creed is backed
- 別靠近圍繩 - 奎迪又被逼退到場邊
into the ropes, trying to avoid those power shots.
他試圖躲開對方的強力攻擊
Damn.
該死
Things just got ugly fast.
場上局勢迅速進入白熱化
And another hard right hand shot, and Creed is in big trouble now.
德拉戈又是一記強勁的右勾拳 奎迪現在真有大麻煩了
Keep moving, Donnie.
腳下別停 多尼
A massive right hand sends Creed reeling.
這一記右勾拳打得奎迪雙腿發軟
He tries to regain his footing.
他在重新調整步調
Creed trying to answer back.
再次試圖回擊
And now a huge hook sends Creed flying through the ropes!
又一記結實的勾拳 打得奎迪翻出了圍繩
Come on, kid.
挺住
Two!
二
Three!
三
Four!
四
Five! Six!
五 六
That's it, that's it, that's it.
很好
Creed! Creed!
奎迪 奎迪
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 你還好嗎 - 還好
Box!
開始
Creed needs something
現在奎迪必須找到
to try to turn this fight around.
扭轉戰局的辦法
Drago just keeps coming.
德拉戈的重拳持續來襲
What a big rib shot!
奎迪左肋又受到重擊
Shit.
糟了
Those were two tremendous right hands to the rib cage.
連續兩記右勾拳挾雷霆之力 打在奎通的胸腔 這沉重的悶響
You could've heard that one in the nosebleed seats.
都能傳到最後一排觀眾的耳朵裏
Creed clearly in pain, as he finds a way to his feet.
奎迪的痛苦顯而易見 但他還是盡力爬了起來
Not ready to give up yet.
他並不打算放棄
I don't know. This is getting dangerous, Jim.
可怎麼說呢 情況不妙啊 吉姆
Okay! Come to me!
你還好嗎 靠近我
And now, Bayless is gonna let him go again.
拜利斯裁判讓雙方繼續比賽
Ready?
準備好
Box!
開始
He comes barreling out of the corner.
奎迪掙扎著離開角落
Huge right hook!
一記右勾拳
Drago trying to end it.
德拉戈想速戰速決
And Creed delivers a big right hand at the bell.
奎迪在結束鈴響之前終於又揮出一拳
Get back! Get back to your corner!
退後 退到角落裏去
Bayless restraining Drago, seemingly frustrated...
拜利斯攔住了德拉戈 德拉戈好像有點受挫
Obey my commands.
聽我指揮
...as he was close to finishing the fight.
畢竟差一點就結束這一回合了
You got to show me something. If not, I'm gonna stop it.
你得趕緊拿出本事來 不然我就得叫停比賽了
Can you fight?
你還能打嗎
Oh, I'm good, I'm good.
我能打 能打
Hell no. I'm calling this fight.
你不能打了 我去叫停比賽
Nigga, don't call this shit.
兄弟 不要叫停
You ain't got to prove shit to nobody.
兄弟 沒必要求別人認同你
Look at you. Your ribs look like they broke.
你看看你 肋骨可能都斷了
You can't call this fight.
別叫停比賽
Hand me my mouthpiece.
把我的護齒拿來
My mouthpiece.
把護齒拿來
Don't do it.
別打了
Now, as we go to round three,
進入第三回合
Adonis Creed has been beaten up and bloodied
阿多尼斯·奎斯已經被打得精疲力盡 身受重傷
by an avalanche of power shots
德拉戈連續不斷的重拳出擊
from Viktor Drago in the first two rounds.
在前兩個回合讓他吃盡了苦頭
And we'll see how much Adonis Creed has left now,
我們看看阿多尼斯·奎迪還剩多少能耐
as he tries to stay alive in the fight.
他掙扎著想活下去 繼續戰鬥
Stop the fight.
不要再打了
Dangerous swings from Drago
德拉戈強悍的臂膀虎虎生威
as Creed desperately tries to hold him off.
奎迪正在拚命抵擋對方的攻擊
Drago's still putting huge pressure on the body.
德拉戈繼續對奎迪的身體發動猛烈攻擊
Come on, stop the fight!
搞什麼 快還擊啊
And another shot by Drago!
德拉戈又揮出一記重拳
Creed seemingly on his last legs!
奎迪似乎已經撐不住了
- Drago on the attack. - Come on, D!
可德拉戈未曾停手 反擊 多尼
Oh, and with a devastating shot to the rib cage.
奎迪的胸腔受到了致命的一擊
Stop! Stop!
停止比賽
This is an obvious disqualification, or so it would appear
德拉戈應該被取消資格 至少看起來是這樣
because Creed was fully down
因為他最後揮出那一拳時
at the moment that Drago landed that last shot.
奎迪已經倒地毫無還手之力了
- No! - You wanna kill somebody?
- 不 - 你這是要殺人麼
- No way, baby. No! - Easy, easy!
- 不行 不行 - 冷靜點
- No. No, no, no! - Come on.
- 不不不 - 別急
No! Just relax.
冷靜點
This arena is completely silent
整個體育場都陷入了沉默
as the audience waits to see
觀眾們都在等待
what will be the condition of young Adonis Creed.
醫護人員會為年輕的阿多尼斯·奎迪 診斷出怎樣的傷勢
Cracked orbital bone, two cracked ribs, grade-3 concussion,
除了眼眶骨破裂 還斷了兩根肋骨 腦震盪程度三級
ruptured kidney, numerous contusions.
腎臟破裂 以及多處挫傷
A ruptured kidney, is that...
腎臟破裂會不會...
His injuries will heal with rest and time,
這些傷好好修養都能痊癒
including the kidney.
包括腎臟
Now, we shouldn't have to resort to surgery,
現在來看沒必要動手術
but we will need to keep him here for at least 48 hours, as a precaution.
不過得留院觀察至少48小時 以防傷勢惡化
Now he's still numb from the morphine, but he'll certainly feel it later.
還有 他現在麻醉勁兒還沒過去 不過再過一會兒肯定會醒的
- Okay. - You okay?
- 好的 - 你還好嗎
Fine, I just gotta sit.
還好 我坐一會兒就行
If you're expecting...
要是你感覺不對
No, I'm fine.
不 我沒事
No, no, seriously. Take it easy, okay?
不 我說真的 別太擔心 好嗎
Excuse me, Dr. Ewell.
打擾一下 尤厄爾醫生
You have a visitor. Right this way.
有人找你 這邊請
Bianca.
比安卡
Listen, I'm so sorry everything went...
我很抱歉事情變成這樣
I should've been there.
我就該守著他
I'm so sorry.
真的對不起
I am.
真的
Me, too.
我也很懊悔
Is it okay if I see him?
我能看看他嗎
What difference do it make to us? We saw what happened.
對我們來說有區別嗎 現場情況大家都看到了
They doing what they supposed to be doing.
裁判和組委會公正裁決就行
I don't care.
這我不管
Right. Okay.
對
Got it.
好 知道了
WBC's not gonna contest the referee's decision,
理事會不打算對裁判的裁決提出異議
so Viktor remains disqualified.
所以維克托維持判罰
Bottom line,
取消比賽資格
you still the champ.
但至少你保住了拳王之名
I'm gonna let you rest, man.
好了 我不打擾你休息了
So, if you need something, you know, I'm outside.
你要是有事就叫我 我就在外面
Got some company, D.
有人來看你 多尼
You did good.
你做得很好
We tried.
我們盡力了
You know, I watched you back in Philadelphia.
知道嗎 你的比賽我在費城看了
You showed a ton of heart. I mean, there's no doubt about it.
你真的非常堅強 沒人能質疑你這點
- Showed a ton of heart. - Heart?
- 你真的很堅強 - 堅強嗎
Man, I ain't trying to hear that shit.
我不要這種狗屁安慰
D. It's Rock.
多尼 別這麼對洛奇
Oh, it's okay. It's all right.
沒關係
No, you guys gotta work it out.
獲取一手資源 拒絕二手資源 從您做起 更多精彩內容 敬請關注微博 @遠鑒字幕組v
I lost the fight before it even started, right?
這場比賽我根本必輸無疑 對嗎
No. No, no.
不 不是
This guy was... He's a big guy, he's strong.
不是 那傢伙個頭那麼大 太壯了
He got the reach on you. He got all kinds of...
臂展又比你長 什麼條件都很好
Oh, now you're trying to train me?
你又想指導我了嗎
Be my coach?
想給我當教練嗎
No, look at me.
你看看我
Look at me.
看看我
What are you still doing here?
你還跑過來幹什麼
Here to pick up the pieces?
你來收拾我的爛攤子嗎
No.
不是
Shouldn't you be in Philly?
幹嗎不待在費城
- Adonis. - No, it's okay.
- 阿多尼斯 - 不 沒關係
I don't want him to get all...
我不想讓他難受
Take care of each other.
你們好好互相照顧
I'm sorry.
對不起
Baby.
好了 寶貝
He loves you, D.
他是愛你的 多尼
Look at me.
看看我
I'm looking right at you, babe.
我一直在看著你 寶貝
How's that baby gonna look at me?
我們的孩子會怎麼看我
Adonis, do you really feel like a champ?
阿多尼斯 你真覺得自己是拳王嗎
Do you think you deserve to keep the belt?
你覺得你配得起金腰帶嗎
Why would you take that fight, Adonis?
你那不叫贏 阿多尼斯
Is this it for Adonis Creed?
阿多尼斯·奎迪就這水平嗎
I'm cool. I'm cool.
沒事
- D, please, let me help you, baby. - I said I can walk.
- 親愛的 讓我幫你吧 - 我說了 我能走
- Please sit... - I said I got it.
求你坐下吧 我說了 我能行
I don't know. Lately, it's like...
我說不好
He hasn't really been himself.
他最近好像跟以前不一樣了
And I get it.
我理解
'Cause he's going through a lot.
畢竟他很受煎熬
He's just starting physical therapy.
他剛剛開始接受物理治療
Trying to get himself right.
在盡力恢復健康
And
但是
he's, uh...
他有點
distant
冷漠
and disconnected.
而且 非常游離
It's like nothing really matters to him right now.
好像現在對他來說什麼都不重要
Including me.
包括我他也不放在心上
Which is new.
這不像他
Yeah.
對
Listen, be there for him, take care of him,
聽著 你得陪著他 好好照顧他
give him your love.
付出你的愛
But also, you gotta realize he's in a place right now
不過你也得明白
that only he can get himself out of.
他現在這個狀態只有靠他自己才能解脫出來
And with everything he's going through...
可他正在經受的這有一切
With everything he's going through?
你管他正在經受什麼呢
You've been in his corner every step of the way.
他這一路上每步都有你的支持
He's a grown man.
可他是個成熟男人了
He's gotta heal from the inside out.
他需要自己從內而外的痊癒
Trust me, I know. I've been there.
相信我 我懂 我經歷過
Feel her?
感覺到了嗎
Yeah.
是
Highlights of Drago silencing critics tonight
德拉戈的精彩表現讓所有質疑都煙消雲散
with a devastating first round knockout of Anthony Novak.
第一回合就勢如破竹 將安東尼·諾瓦克擊倒出局
Here's a post-fight interview with Max Kellerman.
接下來馬克斯·凱勒曼將進行賽後採訪
Viktor, here we are just months
維克托 距離你輸給阿多尼斯·奎迪
since your controversial loss to Adonis Creed.
那場有爭議的比賽 已經好幾個月了
How does this win feel?
這次能贏感覺如何
What loss?
我輸過嗎
Excuse me.
抱歉 我說的是
From your disqualification to Adonis Creed.
你對戰阿多尼斯·奎迪卻被取消資格的事
But how does this feel to you tonight?
好在你今晚贏了 感覺怎麼樣
I don't care. Creed must fight me.
沒什麼感覺 我要再跟奎迪打
And if he doesn't fight you?
如果他不跟你打呢
Then he's no champion.
那他就不算拳王
There you have it, Adonis. Challenge is on the table.
你聽到了嗎 阿多尼斯 對方已經下了戰書了
Viktor!
維克托
What's good?
車不錯
Just maintaining, man. Long time no see, what's up?
好好保養 好久不見 忙什麼呢
Nothing, man. Just been caught up. You know, the house, the baby.
也沒什麼事 就是瞎忙 裝修 待產
You know how it is.
你知道多麻煩
Yeah? How Bianca doing?
好吧 比安卡好嗎
She's good. She's good.
她挺好 挺好
Good, good, good.
好
Listen, man, I've been meaning to hit you up, though.
其實我一直很想聯繫你 兄弟
Commissioner wanna know who we plan to fight next.
理事會想知道我們下一場比賽跟誰打
You ain't gotta fight Drago,
就算不跟德拉戈打
but you gotta fight someone.
你也得跟別人打
You gotta defend the belt.
你得守住金腰帶
Otherwise, it's gonna be vacated.
不然它就要被收回去了
I could set up a little, you know, tune-up fight, kind of.
你知道 我能幫你 選個好打一點的對手
No. You know what, man?
算了 這樣吧
Don't worry about none of that right now.
你現在還是別操心這些事了
Listen, just come on inside.
就進來玩會兒吧
Hit the bag, man, warm up.
打打沙包 熱熱身
Yeah.
好
Yeah, I'm gonna grab my stuff, and I'm gonna meet you in there.
我先去拿裝備 然後再進去找你
All right, man.
好吧 兄弟
Put your body weight into that glove.
用全身的重量出拳
There you go. Lean in it.
這就對了 上前一步
Yeah, I called you, like, a thousand times.
是啊 我都給你打了無數個電話了
Yeah, it's about the light.
是 我家燈壞了
How long?
壞了多久嗎
You want to be specific? Couple years.
仔細算算 有好幾年了吧
Yeah.
對
I mean, how many guys does it take to screw in a light bulb?
只是擰個燈泡而已 用得了幾個人
I'm not joking.
我可沒開玩笑
Can I call you guys back?
我再打給你們好嗎
Yeah.
行
Hey, Ma.
媽
How you doing, kid?
最近好嗎 小子
What are you doing here?
你過來幹什麼
I hope you don't mind,
希望你別介意
your mom asked if I would come out 'cause she's worried about you.
是你媽媽請我過來的 因為她非常擔心你
I am, too.
我也是
I'm good.
我很好
You didn't have to come all this way.
你不用大老遠過來一趟
By train.
我坐火車來的
Three days on a train.
在車上待了三天
It's all right, you know, gives you time to think.
也挺好 你知道 我有思考的時間了
And you watch all these places whipping by the windows like postcards.
可以看著風景 像明信片一樣從窗外閃過
It's quite an experience.
也是一種不錯的經歷
Yeah, I mean, if you say so.
是 你開心就好
Yeah, it was nice.
是 真挺好
This is wonderful.
這個房間太棒了
How you have all this out here.
這兒怎麼能有這麼多的獎盃呢
You could have the same.
你也能有這麼多獎盃
Yeah, I wouldn't say that.
是嗎 我可沒有自信
I mean, not just the shiny stuff,
我說的不只是榮譽
but the better stuff.
有些東西更有價值
Have a better life.
比如更好的人生
Be a better man.
做更好的人
You know, I was thinking about what you were saying about
知道嗎 我其實一直在想你之前質問我說
what smart decisions have I made lately.
我是不是覺得留在原地守著你就是在犯傻
Couldn't think of many.
但沒想出個結果
You know, I wasn't even there when my son's son,
跟你說我兒子的兒子
my grandson,
就是我的親孫子
was born.
他出生時 我沒去
I mean, he's like that tall now probably.
他現在可能都已經長這麼高了
I don't even know him. He doesn't know me.
我卻還不認識他 他也不認識我
It's pathetic.
真的很可悲
Well, why won't you just
那幹嗎不給他
call him?
打電話
It ain't that easy, you know...
沒那麼容易 你懂嗎
Listen,
聽著
I don't want you making the same mistakes I made.
我不希望你重蹈覆轍 犯我犯過的錯
You know what I mean?
你懂我意思嗎
So, you gotta ask yourself,
所以你要問問你自己
what's the valuable stuff?
到底什麼東西才是有價值的
It's like I asked you before.
我以前也問過你類似的問題
What were you really fighting for?
你一路奮戰到底是為了什麼
I was afraid.
我之前很怕
Of this.
榮譽
Expectations.
怕達不到別人的期望
Being the champ.
怕當拳王
I was scared I couldn't do what he couldn't.
我怕我自己達不到爸爸的高度
It's weird.
挺奇怪的
I used to feel like he was apart of me.
我曾覺得他是我的一部分
Now I can't hear him, or that thing,
現在我卻聽不到他的召喚了
that thing that tells me to get in the ring.
我聽不到他讓我上拳台奮戰
Move my feet, keep my hands up.
要腳下不停 一直舉著拳頭
Hit anything that gets in my way.
打倒所有阻擋我的東西
I can't hear it anymore.
我再也聽不到了
I don't even know how I lost.
我都不知道我怎麼輸的
Your mind wasn't right.
你這麼想就不對
And your natural style just won't work with a guy that big.
其實你天生就不適合走你爸爸這樣傳奇的路線
You saying yours was better?
那我更適合你的路線嗎
I won, didn't I?
我贏過 不是嗎
- Good seeing you, Unc. - Great to see you, too.
- 見到你真好 - 我也很開心見到你
I was talking with your mother,
我之前跟你媽媽仔細聊過一陣 她說
and she says you came up with this name for the child.
你給你的孩子起了個名字叫做
- Amara.
- 阿瑪拉 - 阿瑪拉
- Yeah.
- 是 - 好
Why, what's wrong with that?
有什麼問題嗎
No, it's a beautiful name, but it's kind of complicated.
不 沒事 這名字很好聽 就是有點不好念
Why don't you think about something,
為什麼不起一個能讓人
at least I would, a little simpler to say,
至少能讓我念得順口點的
like "Becky" or "Cate," something like that.
比如貝姬或者凱特之類的
Cate Creed?
凱特·奎迪
Cate Creed. Two "C's." Easy to remember.
凱特·奎迪 雙C開頭 挺好記
You do know she's gonna be black, right?
你知道黑人不起這種名字吧
Oh, that's right, I forgot.
對啊 我給忘了
Okay.
好吧
- Hey, Ma. - Yeah.
- 喂 媽 - 好吧
Wait, right now?
等等 現在嗎
- Relax. - Okay.
- 放鬆點 - 好的
- Everything's gonna be fine. - Mmm-hmm.
什麼事都不會有
You just gotta be there for her, okay? That's your job.
你就是到這裏來陪她的 懂嗎 你就做這個
I got you, I got you.
我明白
- And remember... - Yeah.
你記好
Today is gonna be the best day of your life. Right here.
你這輩子的巔峰時刻就是今天 就是在這兒
- All right? - Yeah.
- 懂嗎 - 懂
Best day of your life.
這是你的人生巔峰
- I'm having a baby. - I feel like I'm having a baby.
- 我要有孩子了 - 我感覺跟我有孩子了似的
- Boy! - Hey.
兒子
- What you doing? - I know...
- 你怎麼這麼晚 - 我知道
No, never mind. Just get in here.
不 這沒關係 趕緊到裏面去吧
Okay. Okay, okay.
好
Like I said, I'll be here if you need me.
我說過 你需要我 我一直在的
- All right.
- 好的 - 好
You know, I'm gonna do what I can.
我會盡力去幫他
You being here is more than enough.
你能趕過來 就已經幫他太多了
Thank you.
謝謝
Mr. Balboa?
巴爾博亞先生
- Mmm. - She's here.
孩子生了
Oh, that's great.
那太好了
That's absolutely good.
真是天大的好消息
That's fantastic.
真的是棒極了
Hey, Unc, say hi to your goddaughter.
大叔 跟你的教女打個招呼
Wow. That's quite an honor.
讓我做教父真榮幸
- Let me see you. - Here she is.
- 讓我看看你 - 你看看
Hey, hello, beautiful.
你好啊 小美人
So, nurse...
對了 護士
...what about the test?
檢查什麼時候做
Relax for now.
你們先別急
We'll run an auditory exam as soon as you and Amara get some rest.
聽性腦幹反應的檢查 等比安卡和阿瑪拉都休息好了就會安排人
It's okay, babe.
沒關係 寶貝
Thank God she looks like you.
幸好她長得像你
Yeah, right.
可不是嗎
So, is she gonna feel anything?
這檢查會不會讓她不舒服
No, it's painless. I promise.
不會 這是無痛檢查 保證不疼
Okay. Now that they're in place,
好了 人都就位了
what we're gonna do is give her a series of click stimuli
現在我們要做的就是 給她一些短促的聲音刺激
around 35 decibels
音量大概有三十五分貝
and check her neural responses.
以檢查她的神經系統反應
Is that loud?
聲音大不大
Normal auditory range.
在正常音頻範圍內
Okay.
好了
Here we go.
那就開始
So what exactly are we looking for?
我們具體要看什麼
A reading. Spikes.
讀數 看棘波
So, we're not seeing any waves or spikes, uh,
好吧 目前看不到有任何棘波之類的波形
and given your family history, there is some cause for concern.
因為孩子有家族病史擔心也是很正常的
However, it is very early...
不過現在下結論太早
They're gonna run some more tests.
醫生說還得做檢查
They said it's early, and, uh, sometimes they get false reads.
下結論太早了 有時候也會有誤診的
Let me ask you something.
我問你一件事
What if it ain't okay?
如果真確診了呢
I can't think like that.
我不能這麼想
You gotta, I mean,
得想 不然
how you gonna handle it?
真有事該怎麼辦
I don't wanna go there.
我不願意想
You gonna love her?
你會愛她嗎
How you gonna ask me a question like that, Rock?
你怎麼問得出這種話 洛奇
- Yeah, I'm gonna love her. - Good.
- 我會 我肯定會愛她 - 那就好
'Cause she ain't feeling sorry for herself,
阿瑪拉不會覺得自己有缺陷 所以
and you shouldn't either.
你也不該這麼覺得
You got a little...
這是什麼
Oh, it's boxing gloves.
拳擊手套
- You got it? - Yeah.
- 是吧 - 是
Goodnight Moon. I love that book.
是《晚安 月亮》這書 我很喜歡
Who's that from, babe?
誰送的 寶貝
The unanimous number one contender Viktor Drago
被公認為最強拳壇新人的維克托·德拉戈
has been met with open arms back in Russia,
在他父親的故鄉俄羅斯
his father's home, which is nice.
受到了熱情的歡迎 可謂好事一樁
But the question on everyone's mind is, "Where is Creed?"
不過現在所有人最關心的一件事是 奎迪哪兒去了
If he doesn't choose an opponent soon, he risks forfeiting the title
如果他再不快點選出比賽對手 就有被取消拳王稱號的危險
and personally, I can't imagine him being able to live with that.
而我想 他恐怕會無法承受這樣的打擊
You good?
怎麼了
Yeah. Finally got her to settle.
沒事 總算把她哄睡了
Hey, I need to get out of the house.
我得出去一趟 辦點事情
I was gonna go over to the studio.
我本來得去工作室的
You mind watching her until I get back?
我回來之前你能照看她嗎
Yeah, of course.
能 當然能
Cool.
好
Okay, okay.
好啦 好啦
Yeah.
好的
You okay?
還好嗎
Yeah, I got it. Yeah.
我來 我來就好 對
Okay.
好
Bye.
拜拜
Baby.
寶貝
Baby, please.
乖 乖 別哭了
Hey, you hungry, right? Hey, baby, you hungry?
你餓了 對不對 你餓了 沒關係
It's Mary Anne. Please leave a message.
我是瑪麗·安 有事請留言
Hey, Ma. Listen, listen.
媽 聽著
She won't stop crying. Can you just tell me how to...
阿瑪拉一直在哭 你能不能告訴我
Can you tell me how to make her stop crying?
告訴我怎麼能讓她不哭
Call me back when you get this message, okay?
你聽到就給我回電 好嗎
Hey, what's up, baby girl?
你怎麼啦 乖女兒
Hey, no.
別哭
It's okay, baby. No, no.
沒事的 寶貝
No, don't cry. No, not again, please.
別哭 別再哭了
Please.
求你了
No, look, look, look.
你看
You see that?
看見了嗎
Look, look, look.
看這兒
I'm right here.
我在這兒呢
I'm sorry.
對不起
Hey. No, no, there you go.
別哭 來抱抱
I know.
我知道
Mmm-hmm. Daddy's being a bitch, I know.
最近爸爸表現很糟 我知道
How'd you do?
她怎麼樣
She's a fighter.
她非常堅強
Just like her dad.
跟她爸爸一樣
Just like her mom, too.
也跟她媽媽-樣
I have to fight him again.
我得跟他再打一次
I don't wanna be that person to stop you.
我不想做你的絆腳石
But I don't wanna end up like your mom, alone.
但我也不想最後和你媽媽一樣孤獨
I feel you.
我明白
Do you?
是嗎
And it's not just us anymore, D.
我們都已經有孩子了 多尼
I know it sounds crazy doing all this all over again.
我知道再去自討苦吃一次聽起來很瘋狂
But this won't be the end of me.
但我不會被輕易擊潰
Or you.
你也不會
It can't be, 'cause we a team.
絕對不會 因為我們一條心
We weren't a team when you took the fight the last time.
上次你擅自應戰就沒跟我一條心
You right.
你說得對
I'm sorry.
對不起
I shouldn't have put you through that.
我不該讓你受這份罪
Then why?
那你何苦呢
Why do it again?
何苦還要打
What do you have to prove?
你到底要證明什麼
It's not about that.
跟證明什麼無關
You wouldn't be any good to anybody if you didn't do what you love.
而是人一旦放棄熱愛的事業就會失去自己的價值
You wouldn't be able to breathe, right?
會連活都活不下去 對嗎
Well, I wouldn't be any good to anybody if I don't handle this the right way.
所以如果不能好好把這件事做個了斷 那我以後就算廢了
But I need you.
我需要你的支持
Both of you.
我也捨不得女兒
I'll beat him.
我一定會贏
You better.
你只能贏
You gotta think about this real hard.
這件事你必須好好考慮清楚
You got people that need you now.
你現在可是有家人需要照顧的
That's exactly why I can't lose.
正因為這樣我才更不能輸
Buddy said the fight has to be in Russia.
巴迪說要比只能在俄羅斯比
Take it or leave it.
不然就別比
Russia?
俄羅斯
On their turf.
他們的地盤
So Russia it is.
那就去俄羅斯
What you think, Rock?
你說呢 洛奇
It's a clear advantage if it comes down to a judge's decision.
要是最後得靠裁判打分定輸贏 他們是有優勢的
Well, then we can't let it get to a judge's decision, right?
那就只好把他徹底擊倒 不勞裁判費心了 對嗎
Oh, shit.
真要命
Call the promoter.
那聯繫巴迪嗎
So we train here tomorrow, 5:00 a.m.
明早五點在這裏訓練嗎
No, I got other plans.
不 我有個新的計劃
- You mean, you wanna go to Philly? - No.
- 你是說回費城去嗎 - 不
Listen, you wanna change things in a big way,
聽著 你要是想一鼓作氣扭轉 乾坤
then you need to make some big changes.
那就必須先讓自己脫胎換骨
You gotta be messing with me, right?
來這兒練 你逗我嗎
Heard this is a place where fighters go,
聽說如果有哪個拳手想從頭來過
you know, to start over.
都會來這兒練
Get reborn.
讓自己涅槃重生
What took y'all so long?
怎麼這麼晚才到
This some wild shit.
找不到地方上廁所嗎
Yeah, sure looks like hell to me.
是 對我來說簡直是地獄
Since you're going back to hell, you might as well get used to it.
既然你之後又要挑戰地獄難度的對手 那就快點適應這裏
Let's go.
開始吧
Go for it.
加油干
Harder.
用力點
Harder!
還得用力
Keep going.
堅持
Build that neck.
脖子練結實
Okay, man up.
來 爺們點
No.
不用
I'm good.
我沒事
That's the fight it's gonna be. Toe-to-toe. Get used to it.
在這兒打就這規矩 先腳碰腳 習慣就好
Box!
開始
Take it to the body.
扛住 用身體扛住
Take it! Fight the pain.
忍住 要打敗疼痛
You all right?
還好嗎
Get back in there.
把腳伸進去 伸進去再來
Get back in there. Protect yourself.
保護好自己
Come on, get up, kid.
加油 起來 孩子
Get up.
站起來
Keep moving.
腳下別停
That's it.
這就對了
We're just minutes away from the fight
再過幾分鐘
the whole world has been waiting to see.
這場全球矚目的世紀大戰就將開始了
The rematch between Adonis Creed and Viktor Drago
這一次是阿多尼斯·奎迪與維克托·德拉戈
for the heavyweight championship of the world.
第二次為爭奪世界重量級拳王開戰
The unique thing about this fight, Jim,
賽前有一點值得有提 吉姆
is Adonis Creed comes in a 25-to-1 underdog,
那就是阿多尼斯·奎迪在拳擊博彩中的賠率只有1:25 非常不被看好
and he's the champ!
他可是衛冕的一方
Well, it's gonna be fascinating to see
那相信大家都很好奇
what that does to Creed's mindset as he enters the ring.
這件事對他踏上拳台後的心態 會有什麼影響
Not to mention Drago's.
德拉戈又會怎麼想呢
Drago! Drago! Drago!
德拉戈 德拉戈 德拉戈
And there he is.
德拉戈上場了
Ladies and gentlemen, Viktor Drago! Making his way into the arena.
先生們 女士們 維克托·德拉戈 現在正向體育場走來
He does not have the belt, but to everyone here in Russia
雖然還沒有奪得金腰帶 但是在俄羅斯觀眾看來
and to many around the world,
甚至在全世界很多觀眾看來
he is the true heavyweight champion.
他才是真正的重量級拳王
It's time, kid.
要上場了 小子
There was no way Creed could have run from this fight.
奎迪與德拉戈的這一戰無可避免
There was such high demand for Adonis to step back in the ring with Viktor.
因為粉絲的呼聲太高 希望他重返拳台與德拉戈再戰
And I'm sure Ivan feels good to be back home after all these years.
我相信伊凡時隔多年回到祖國 應該感覺不錯
♪ Ran the whole way
一路走來
♪ Ran the whole thing
一戰到底
♪ Never ran away
永不逃避
♪ Never been afraid
絕不恐懼
♪ Never gonna break
永不停歇
♪ Never halfway
絕不放棄
♪ I don't know if I can take it
不知道自己能否承受
♪ I can take it, I can take it anymore
能否承受這一切
♪ I don't know if I could do it
不知道自己能否實現
If it wasn't for who I'd do it for
如果不是為了最初的那人努力
♪ Doesn't make sense But it makes dollars
什麼毫無意義 卻是生財之道
♪ And I wanna spend it all with you
我願和你一起浪費
♪ Against the world But I'm with you
和你起對抗世界
♪ I would go to war
如果你倒下
♪ 'Long as you're down
我願踏入戰爭
♪ Won't let you down
不會讓你失望
Remember why you're climbing these steps.
別忘了你是為什麼要踏上拳台
Come on up, champ.
上吧 拳王
This is it, Jim. Creed versus Drago part two.
終於等到了 吉姆 奎迪與德拉戈火花四濺的二度對決
Creed looks good tonight,
奎迪今晚狀態不錯
but it's impossible to forget what happened to him
不過他上次與德拉戈對決時的慘狀
the last time he stepped into the ring with Drago.
我到現在還感覺歷歷在目
Numerous injuries, not least of all, a nasty broken rib
他傷痕纍纍 其中最嚴重的 是一根肋骨被打至斷裂
and a ruptured kidney.
還有一側腎臟破裂
A huge difference in this fight
這次他有一大變化
is he's got former champ Rocky Balboa back in his corner.
那就是他請回了著名教練 前拳王洛奇·巴爾博亞作為指導
And Rocky assures everyone
有洛奇坐鎮
this fight will be very different from its predecessor.
本場比賽奎迪應該會有脫胎換骨的表現
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. This is it.
晚上好 女士們先生們 終於等到今晚了
Twelve rounds of boxing
本次十二回合制的
for the heavyweight championship of the world!
世界重量級拳王衛冕賽 即將開戰
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士們 先生們
let's get ready to rumble!
讓我們為拳手們吶喊吧
You can feel the nervous energy in the arena tonight, Jim.
你能感覺到今晚拳台上一觸即發的緊張感 吉姆
Creed has some courage to get back into the ring
奎迪竟然有膽量再次面對
with a man who nearly ended his career.
曾經差點終結自己職業生涯的對手
A man who is hungry to be champ.
對拳王之位志在必得的德拉戈
Fighters,
兩位
I want good, clean fight.
我要一場公平乾淨的比賽
Break when I tell you to break.
我說分開 你們就分開
You go to your corner when I tell you to go to your corner.
我讓你們退回場角 你們就回到場角
Touch gloves.
碰拳套 祝你們好運
Rocky Balboa and Ivan Drago sharing the ring
洛奇·巴爾博亞和伊凡·德拉戈
for the first time in 30 years.
時隔三十年再一次站上了同一個拳台
If anyone knows how to take on a slugger like Drago, it would be Rocky.
所有人都知道 要備戰德拉戈這麼強的對手 只能找洛奇
You know you got the fire in your gut,
你知道你心裏燒著怎樣的火
and I know you'll do what needs to be done.
而我知道你會在拳台上怎樣活
Because now, you know what you're fighting for.
因為現在 你已經明白自己為什麼而戰
Viktor overwhelmed Creed's previous game plan,
德拉戈上一次狠狠壓制奎迪的比賽戰術
and I think it got in Adonis' head.
現在阿多尼斯應該還有陰影
It's gonna be interesting to see how Rocky Balboa has prepared Creed
所以我們都非常期待看到洛奇·巴爾博亞的訓練成果
for what is surely to become an all-out brawl.
看他如何幫助奎迪備戰這場激烈對抗
Ready?
好了嗎
Box.
開始
And we're underway.
比賽正式開始
Drago comes out swinging with two hooks that Creed avoids.
德拉戈連續打出了兩記勾拳 但奎迪躲開了
And a big right-hand right out of the gate.
德拉戈又揮出一記重重的右勾拳
Watch that right, Donnie.
小心右拳 多尼
Drago a bit surprised as Creed shakes that punch off.
德拉戈有點意外 奎迪竟然躲開了他的攻擊
Drago is pressing hard, but Creed is not backing off.
一記右直拳 德拉戈步步緊逼 不過奎迪並沒有就此退縮
Keep moving, keep moving.
腳下別停
Creed working a little bit closer to Drago tonight.
奎迪今晚與德拉戈對打 採取了貼身戰術
That is a vicious combination by Creed.
剛才奎迪鬥志昂揚地打出子一套組合拳
And now a right hand by Drago.
剛剛德拉戈揮出了右拳
Here we go, Drago applying pressure.
發力了 德拉戈開始向對手反擊了
- Out the corner! - Come on, Donnie!
別進場角 出來 多尼
Creed manages to slip away.
奎迪一個閃身 離開了場角
Let's get it.
放馬過來
Yeah, what's up?
怎麼樣
Now they're squaring off in the middle of the ring, toe-to-toe.
兩個人在拳台中央周旋
Taking blows.
互有命中 勢均力敵
Creed staying in his face.
奎迪連續打中對手的臉
And there's the bell! As a wild first round comes to an end.
鈴聲響了 激烈的第一回合比賽已經結束了
Go to your corner.
回角落去
Drago frustrated.
德拉戈有些挫敗
Creed is looking like a different fighter tonight, Max.
今晚的奎迪就像換了個人似的 馬克斯
- That's it, D! That's it! - Yes!
很好 就該這樣
Oh, yeah, who's saying Drago now, though?
看誰還給德拉戈加油
See, all that work in the desert paid off, right?
荒地裏那些苦沒白吃吧 是
Yeah, you got him. You got him thinking.
你得手了 他就得想辦法了
He wasn't expecting what you're bringing.
他本來沒想到你會這麼打
Now, he's gonna bring the heat the next round, but you're ready for it.
下一回合他攻勢會更猛 但你準備好了
He overextends his right hand.
他右拳用得最多
You gonna counter with the right
你先把拳頭擋住
and crack him with the left. You got that?
再用左拳擊垮他 懂了嗎
Extend the right, crack him with the left.
他出右拳 我就出左拳
He'll never expect it. His old man did the same thing to me.
他絕對想不到這招 你爸當初就是這麼對付我的
One early observation, Max.
據我剛才的觀察 馬克斯
I think Creed is withstanding Drago's combinations
我覺得奎迪今晚在抵抗德拉戈的組合拳時
much better tonight than in the first fight.
表現得比上一場要好太多了
Box.
開始
And round two begins.
第二回合比賽開始
Drago with a huge left hook.
德拉戈揮出了強勁的左勾拳
And a big right hand.
接著右手一記重拳
Drago on the attack again, now driving Creed back into the ropes.
德拉戈又發起一輪猛攻 現在把奎迪逼到圍繩邊了
He's overextending the right! Watch the right!
他一直在出右拳 小心右拳
A right and a left for Creed.
奎迪左右開弓 重拳出擊
Huge uppercut has Creed holding on now.
好一記上勾拳 奎迪抱住了德拉戈
Drago throws him off into the corner.
德拉戈擺脫了 並將奎迪逼進場角
- Get out of that corner! - Get out of the corner!
- 離開場角 - 快離開場角
And Drago throws Creed to the canvas.
德拉戈把奎迪摔在了拳台上
What's going on?
這是幹什麼呢
Shades of the first fight,
上次比賽也是這樣
but Drago showing restraint this time.
不過這一次德拉戈稍微克制了一點
You good?
還行嗎
Yes, I'm good.
行 沒問題
- Box. - Drago explodes from the break.
- 開始 - 比賽短暫中止之後 德拉戈徹底爆發了
And Creed is down!
奎迪倒地了
A flurry of heavy shots!
他沒擋住這一連串颶風般的重拳
Drago's power is just incredible.
德拉戈的力量簡直是太驚人了
Three.
三
Four.
四
Take the eight count. Take the full eight.
等夠八秒 等夠八秒再起來
Creed taking his time on the canvas.
奎迪正趴在地上 抓緊時間調整
Six.
六
Stay down! Breathe!
趴著別動 深呼吸
He's listening to Rocky, who has been in this situation before.
奎迪聽從了洛奇的指示 因為洛奇曾有過類似的比賽經歷
Eight.
八
And Creed is back on his feet. Beats the count.
就在讀秒結束前 奎迪站起來了
- Ready? - Yeah, let's go.
- 好了嗎 - 好了 開始吧
Box.
開始
Tie him up. Don't fight him. Tie him up.
纏住他 別跟他打 纏住他
Drago is right back at it.
德拉戈重整旗鼓 再次猛攻
So, with the knockdown and those hard shots at the end,
剛剛一個擊倒 加上最後的連續重拳
that round clearly goes to Viktor Drago.
這一回合 德拉戈的贏面明顯要大於奎迪
And you could just feel he's gaining momentum.
而且能感覺到他的攻勢一波比一波猛
You knew this was gonna be a war, right?
這次本來就是場硬仗 對吧
You knew that going in there.
你來之前就知道了
From now on, it's who wants it more,
從現在起拼的 就是誰更想贏
and who's got more heart.
誰的意志更堅定
Don't let him crack you. You stay on the outside, you're gonna get hurt.
別讓他打垮你 你在外圍轉只能挨打
You stay on the inside, you'll tear him up.
近身對打才能打敗他
I'm telling you, it's all about pressure.
關鍵是得向他施壓
If you wanna give pain, you gotta be willing to take the pain.
如果想讓對方痛苦 自己得先忍受痛苦
Come on!
來啊
- Yes!
很好
Round four is another brutal display
第四回合 又是一個殘酷激烈的回合
as Creed takes a lot of punishment from Drago.
奎迪被動地受著德拉戈的連續重擊
Drago is not slowing down.
德拉戈絲毫沒有放緩自己的攻勢
Landing a big shot after the bell.
鈴響之後 還對奎迪使出了一記重拳
What is your problem?
你們是怎麼回事
The violent chess match continues, Jim.
這兩位殘暴的對抗還在繼續 吉姆
Oh, and Creed is down again.
奎迪又一次被擊倒了
Donnie, get up.
多尼 起來
Drago clearly dominating this fight, but Creed will not give up.
德拉戈明顯佔據了上風 不過奎迪也沒想放棄
He is taking a lot of punishment.
他這幾回合可是受了不少罪
You gotta stay in his face. Look at me.
你就貼身緊逼 看著我
You gotta stay in his face.
你要做的就是貼身緊逼
And when you see an opportunity, you go after it.
一旦你等到機會 就全力出擊
There you are!
這就對了
Drago is cut now.
德拉戈的節奏亂了
As we enter round eight,
第八回合結束
we are deeper into this fight than anyone expected.
比賽進行到這個階段 超乎我們所有人的預料
Creed must sense he's behind. He's trying to force the action.
奎迪自知比分落後 開始逼自己發動進攻
Yes, baby!
很好 兒子
What we are seeing tonight is Adonis Creed
今晚我們一路看著阿多尼斯·奎迪
standing up to the awesome power of Viktor Drago.
站上拳台正面迎擊實力非同凡響的維克托·德拉戈
He's not going anywhere.
他絲毫沒有退縮
Viktor Drago looks tired, Max.
維克托看上去很累 馬克斯
Keep in mind, he's never had to go past the 4th round in a professional fight.
要知道之前他打職業拳賽的時候 從來不必打第四回合
- Hey! What was that? - Take the point, ref!
- 他在幹什麼 - 扣分啊 裁判
And Drago drops Creed
德拉戈連出兩記重拳
- with two nasty body shots. - Come on!
又讓奎迪倒在了拳台上
- He held him and hit him. - One.
- 哪有拽著人打的 - 一
Viktor holding and maybe getting away with something there.
維克托拽住對手攻擊 卻僥倖逃過了判罰
The ref must not have seen it.
可能是裁判沒有看清
Come on.
過來
I think Rocky Balboa has a decision to make here, Jim.
我看洛奇·巴爾博亞得考慮是不是該認輸了 吉姆
He knows better than anyone
他比任何人都清楚
how this same story played out three decades ago.
三十年前他遇到同樣的情況時 是什麼樣的結局
Donnie, Donnie, talk to me.
多尼 跟我說話
Donnie.
多尼
Your ribs?
你的肋骨
You think it's broke?
斷了嗎
What do you wanna do, Donnie?
你想怎麼辦 多尼
You wanna call it?
要我認輸嗎
I didn't think so.
我想也不是
Now he's gonna come after you,
接下來他會窮追不捨
and he's gonna try to break on that rib some more.
攻擊你受傷的肋骨 讓它徹底斷掉
But that's okay.
但沒關係
'Cause you like the pain. You can take it.
因為你享受疼痛 你扛得住
You know why? Because you're dangerous.
為什麼 因為你很強大
- I'm dangerous. - That's right.
- 我很強大 - 說得沒錯
Ten seconds out.
還有十秒
Now here we go with round ten
現在到了第十回合的比賽
of what has become a war of attrition.
這場比賽已經成了一場艱苦的拉鋸戰
Drago seemingly ahead on the scorecards, but Creed refusing to back down.
- 目前計分牌顯示德拉戈暫時領先 - 但奎迪 他完全沒打算認輸
That's it, Donnie. Good.
就這麼打 多尼 很好
Creed using whatever he has left in the tank.
奎迪現在已經是使出了渾身的力氣
Drago working the body.
德拉戈在集中攻擊他的身體
Tie him up!
纏住他
And down goes Creed again.
奎迪再次被擊倒在地
And this could be the end of the fight.
這場比賽可能要到此為止了
Get up, D.
起來 多尼
No man should be able to fight through that beating,
沒有人能抗得住德拉戈那樣的重拳
but Adonis Creed wills himself off the canvas.
但阿多尼斯·奎迪靠意志再次站了起來 奎迪
- What's your name? - Creed.
- 你叫什麼 - 奎迪
What's your name?
你叫什麼
Creed!
奎迪
Box!
開始
Adonis Creed knows there is no way around Viktor Drago.
阿多尼斯·奎迪知道 維克托·德拉戈是他必須跨越的障礙
He has to go through him.
他一定要攻克他
Dig!
重錘
Dig! Dig!
重錘 重錘
Creed suddenly finding another gear!
奎迪突然像多了個馬達一樣
Come on!
加油
Drago's on his heels.
德拉戈有些站不穩了
And down goes Drago!
德拉戈被擊倒了
That's it! That's right!
這就對了 就該這樣
What a wild turn of events.
拳台上的局勢瞬間扭轉了 一
Two.
二
Donnie, he gets up, you go after him.
多尼 等他一起來 就乘勝追擊
Three.
三
Four.
四
Five.
五
- Six. - Drago beats the count.
- 六 - 德拉戈及時站起來了
I can't believe either of these guys are still on their feet.
真不敢相信 這兩位到這一刻居然還能站得住
Box.
開始
Drago seemingly so far ahead on points, he just needs to stay upright
德拉戈在比分上應該是大幅領先 他只要不被擊倒在地
and make it to the end.
撐到最後就能贏
Here comes Creed again, driving Drago back into the ropes.
奎通再次進攻 讓德拉戈在圍繩邊動彈不得
- Dig! Dig! Dig! - Yeah!
重錘 重錘 打倒他
Come on, take him down!
加油 把他擊倒
Come on, baby.
加油 寶貝
And Viktor Drago is down!
維克托·德拉戈被擊倒在地
Again!
第二次了
What a turn this fight has taken.
這場比賽局勢變化太大了
Creed doubled over in pain
奎迪已經疼得直不起腰了
as Drago tries to pick himself up off the floor.
而德拉戈正努力從拳台上爬起來
Drago summons the strength, manages to make the count.
德拉戈拼盡了全力 在讀秒結束前站了起來
They're still swinging, Max.
他們還在揮動看拳頭 馬克斯
Creed continuing to connect.
奎迪還在持續不斷地攻擊
And this is becoming hard to watch, Jim.
這場面已經讓人不忍心看下去了 吉姆
I don't think Drago has anything left,
在我看來德拉戈已經無力反抗了
but he refuses to give up.
但他就是死活不肯放棄
And that's it! It's over!
好心 比賽結束
Drago's corner throws in the towel.
老德拉戈作為教練 扔毛巾認輸了
And Adonis Creed defends his title.
而阿多尼斯·奎迪衛冕了拳王之位
Defends his name.
也守住了名譽
Creates his own legacy.
更創造出了屬於自己的傳奇
He is still the heavyweight champion of the world.
他依舊是手握金腰帶的世界重量級拳王
And the Russian crowd is standing and cheering for the American fighter.
現場的俄羅斯觀眾 此刻也都紛紛起立為這位美國拳手鼓掌喝彩
Where's B at? Where's B?
比安卡呢 比安
Easy, easy, easy.
慢點 慢點
Hey, back up. Everybody back up. We need air.
讓開 大家都讓開一點 讓他透口氣
Yeah.
好了
- We did it.
- 我們做到了 - 我們做到了
- Let's go home. - Let's go, D.
- 沒關係 - 我們回家
I'm good, Ma. I'm good.
我沒事 媽 我沒事
- I did it. I did it. - You did it.
- 我做到了 - 你是做到了
Hey, Unc.
大叔
It's your time.
現在是你的時代
Hey, okay, back up.
退後
What's up, Pops?
老爸
I'm sorry it took me so long to come see you.
我很抱歉一直沒來看你
I'm not sure how this is supposed to go. Um...
我不知道跟你說什麼好
I guess I should tell you that Mom's doing pretty good.
我猜你應該想知道 媽媽過得很不錯
You know, she's holding up.
你知道她很堅強
So is Rocky.
洛奇也是
- Thanks a lot. - Thank you.
麻煩你了
He's a tough dude.
他也很堅強
I can see why you liked him.
我能明白你為什麼喜歡他
I also see why you wanted to fight him, too.
我也明白你為什麼想跟他較量
Look, um,
聽著
I just came here to tell you that...
我就是想來告訴你
That I did it.
我證明了自己
But I didn't do it for you.
但我不是為你
Or because of them.
也不是求別人認同
I did it because it was my fight.
我這麼做 只因為這是我的戰鬥
And when I stepped into that ring,
當我踏上那個拳台
it wasn't just about me.
我代表的不只是自己
Hello.
你好
You must be Logan.
你就是羅根吧
Yes. Who are you?
對 你是誰
Lo, who is it?
羅根 是誰來了
Sometimes we think we have to do it all on our own.
有些事只能我們親力親為
Hey, Robert.
你好 羅伯特
But we don't.
但我們沒有去做
I was just around in the neighborhood, so...
我正好在附近辦點事
This is your grandfather.
這是你爺爺
You look just like his mother.
你長得真像你爸爸的媽媽
Yeah, I know.
是啊
I wanna introduce you to somebody.
我想介紹個人給你
Do you wanna come inside?
你想進來坐坐麼
Yeah.
好
Give me that.
來抱一個
- Is that a ball? - Yeah.
- 那是個球麼 - 是的
- Wanna play catch? - Yes.
- 來玩我扔你接吧 - 好
There you go.
來吧
This
這位
is your granddaughter. Amara.
是你的孫女 阿瑪拉
Say what's up to Pop-Pop.
那位是你的爺爺